<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article>
    <title>How CCNA will help me?</title>
    <author></author>
    <section>
        <p>
            

Lets get started with little backdrop on classifications of Cisco certifications.  
<br>Cisco provides 3 Levels of certifications, </br>
<p>
<pre>
Associate
    o CCNA/CCENT/CCDA
Professional
    o	CCNP/CCDP/CCSP/CCIP/CCVP
Expert
    o	CCIE 
    (Routing and Switching, Security, Service Provider, Storage NW and Voice)
</pre>
</p>
These levels can be completed through 6 different paths based on choice and job requirement. 

<p> Apart from these, Cisco also provides specialist certifications such as,
<pre>
• Cisco Routing and Switching Field Specialist
• Cisco Data Center Networking Infrastructure Design Specialist
</pre>
</p>

<p>
For further information on above mentioned streams/courses visit Cisco certifications page. 
</p>

<p>CCNA – Cisco Certified Network Associate is an Associate level certification. CCNA acts a foundation to pursue higher level Cisco certifications. 
</p>
Lets get on straight with CCNA syllabus and value add which you’ll get with this certification. <br>
</br>

<p>
<pre>
The course curriculum of CCNA includes following,

• OSI model and industry standards 
• Network topologies 
• IP addressing, including subnet masks 
• Networking components 
• Basic network design
• Beginning router configurations 
• Routed and routing protocols
• Advanced router configurations 
• LAN switching theory and VLANs 
• Advanced LAN and LAN switched design 
• Novell IPX 
• Threaded case studies
• WAN theory and Design 
• WAN technology, PPP, Frame Relay, ISDN 
• Network troubleshooting 
• National SCANS Skills 
• Threaded case study

</pre>
</p> 
<p>As we see, CCNA starts with networking basics, covers IP addressing and subnetting which is critical to network setup, introduces network design concepts which clearly gives insight about local LAN and WAN network setup and goes on with core Cisco router configurations w.r.t PPP, Frame Relay, ISDN and VLANs.
</p>

<p>Now a days CCNA has become the most common requirement for any job in Hardware and Networking field. Also, taking up this certification/course gives insight about general computer networking, which helps the candidate to build enough confidence in setting up networks and facing interview in the field of Networking. 
</p>

<p>Some of the fields/requirements where CCNA is critical are listed below,
<pre>
• Network Engineer for ISP’s Network Operation Center
• Network Administrator
• System Administrator
• DSL Engineer in Broadband service providers
• DSL Installation Engineers
• Router and Switch Engineers in ISPs
• Hardware Networking Engineers
</pre>
</p>

<p> Irrespective of presence of Cisco routers in the company premises, companies prefer candidates to have CCNA certificate to qualify for the interview. 
Hence CCNA always adds value to candidate looking out for career in the field of Networking.
</p>
 
        </p>
        <p><b>--Razikh</b><br/>
	</p>
    </section>
</article>
