<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article>
    <title>Path 2 Success</title>
    <author><a href="mailto:razikh@gmail.com">-Razikh</a></author>
    <section>
        <p>
            I always believe that I can achieve whatever I want or others can.
            I do admire good qualities in terms of Personal or Social or Technical
            skills which others possess and which are better than what I do.
            And the people who are successful always fascinate me. I always used
            to think, what is it which separates these people from people like me? 
	    Though we have our own special qualities but still not successful 
            like them. I was determined to find the secret of success.
        </p>
        <p>What could have been a better way to start off than knowing what 
            these successful people had to say about their secret of success? 
            Yes, I started by reading books written by popular public speakers, 
            authors, psychiatrists etc., I found that one thing is been 
            emphasized everywhere, 'Individual Will'. That is, Its up to us to 
            make our world beautiful. Only thing we can change in this world is 
            'Our Attitude'. The power to succeed is within us. At end of these 
            explorations, I was finally delighted to find out what I wanted, key 
            to success. If you are ready to experience this new way of 
            living life, then Jump In;
        </p>
        <p>What could have been a better way to start off than knowing what 
            these successful people had to say about their secret of success? 
            Yes, I started by reading books written by popular public speakers, 
            authors, psychiatrists etc., I found that one thing is been 
            emphasized everywhere, 'Individual Will'. That is, Its up to us to 
            make our world beautiful. Only thing we can change in this world is 
            'Our Attitude'. The power to succeed is within us. At end of these 
            explorations, I was finally delighted to find out what I wanted, key 
            to success. If you are ready to experience this new way of 
            living life, then Jump In;<br/>
        </p>
        <p>What could have been a better way to start off than knowing what 
            these successful people had to say about their secret of success? 
            Yes, I started by reading books written by popular public speakers, 
            authors, psychiatrists etc., I found that one thing is been 
            emphasized everywhere, 'Individual Will'. That is, Its up to us to 
            make our world beautiful. Only thing we can change in this world is 
            'Our Attitude'. The power to succeed is within us. At end of these 
            explorations, I was finally delighted to find out what I wanted, key 
            to success. If you are ready to experience this new way of 
            living life, then Jump In;<br/>
        </p>
        <p>Ok, if you are reading this, then it means you believe that you 
        can be successful. So you have already achieved first step ;). With 
        this Belief (Confidence) , let's go further...
        </p>
        <p>I found that to achieve success in any activity, we must 
        imbibe few good qualities/practices. I call this set of 
        qualities which are essential to succeed as <b>'TI2' (Pronounced as 
        TI square).</b>
        </p>
        <p><b>TI2</b> stands for 'Totally Into It'. What are the qualities which 
			makes up<b> TI2</b>,
        </p>
        <ul>
                <li><b>Passion/Interest (P)</b></li>
                <li><b>Confidence (C)</b></li>
                <li><b>Concentrate/Attentive (Ca)</b></li>
                <li><b>Learn from Mistakes (E)</b></li>
                <li><b>Positive Attitude (Pa)</b></li>
        </ul>
        <p>
            This makes up <b>PCCEP</b> :). Yup formula to success. <br/>
            Doesn't this seem simple to you?? Neither to me initially, but when 
            I implemented them in my daily activities, they seem to be a cake 
            walk to achieve!! To make things much clear, will put down my 
            experience with <b>TI2</b>,
        </p>
        <p>I have an habit of changing my handwriting style because I always 
            desire my handwriting to look attractive Though I'm least bothered 
            about how legible it is :) Whenever I encounter an attractive 
            script, I try to pen in/learn the same. So when I was writing about 
            TI2, I thought why not apply it for my handwriting as well. Within 
            matter of few lines I could find the difference in my writing style, 
            It had become more straight &amp; attractive, something which I had only 
            thought of earlier. How did this happen within matter time?? <br/>
            Simple, as a matter of fact, I always had passion (P) to make 
            my handwriting more attractive. Then I became attentive (Ca) about 
            the way I was holding the pen, the way characters were written, the 
            way I was holding Notepad etc., &amp; I quickly started 
            positioning (E) them &amp; myself in the way which helped me to pen down 
            characters in a more attractive way. Though through the way, 
            few words/characters were ripping apart in the process, I was 
            positive about the outcome at the end, attractive, legible 
            handwriting better than earlier existing one. Moving ahead I'm 
            sure things would be much better (Pa).
        </p>
        <p>You might be thinking, how this example, would help in other 
        career oriented activities. My answer is, every activity requires 
        individual attention to be successfully completed. I'll tell 
        you about my career life. <br/>
        Right from days of my engineering studies, I was passionate about 
        Linux &amp; Networking. I strongly believe that, I could complete my 
        engineering with good scores only because of subjects related to 
        Linux &amp; networking. As I was not at all interested to take up 
        Computer Science initially though I was forced to do so. But life 
        did change rapidly when I started exploration about Linux &amp; 
        Networking. My scores changed from mere just First class to 
        Distinctions pushing my final result to First Class with 
        Distinction. After studies, I was determined to pursue career in 
        networking, though there were easy ways to get into Programming 
        which most of the students do. I took my first networking 
        certification. I had always heard that getting this 
        certification is tough. I never felt that way because I enjoyed 
        those networking concepts thoroughly &amp; within 2 weeks of training, I 
        had passed it. The next week I had landed with the first Job in 
        Networking. I continued to pursue careers in Linux &amp; QA with 
        completion of well known certifications. Today I find myself in the 
        domain I always wanted to, working on Linux &amp; 
        Networking. I continue to learn &amp; explore lot about them everyday. 
        And I'm delighted &amp; happy to be in a position where others find my 
        expertise as useful to learn &amp; implement in the current project &amp; 
        their career. <br/>
        Though I had no clue about TI2, in those days, still we 
        can find the same pattern in my career path, Passion towards Linux &amp; 
        Networking (P). Confidence to get job in the domain I always wanted 
        &amp; Getting certifications (C &amp; Ca). <br/>
        If you look back into your career path, or life you will find 
        similar pattern as well, which further confirms the importance 
        of these qualities.
        </p>
        <p>You might be thinking, these examples explain about the way to be 
        successful in activities which you like, but how to win over 
        activities which you don't like or which you encounter once in a 
        while??
        </p>
        <p>Ok, let us see how can we implement TI2, in these activities. As 
        a matter fact, you cannot win (successful completion not just a 
        formal completion) over any activity, you must be interested in it. 
        So, develop interest in that activity (P). Always be confident (C) 
        about your involvement, keep saying to yourself, 'You can do It'. 
        And more importantly, be always ready to accept Mistakes. Be 
        responsible to whatever you do. If you have done some mistake, 
        accept it. Always remember, Learning from mistakes (E) drives you 
        towards success. And you got to concentrate on whatever you 
        do. If you are not fully involved (Ca), then you can never achieve 
        success in any activity. Always have positive attitude towards your 
        progress. Even if you fail once or twice, be determined give it a 
        shot again and win over it.
        </p>
        <p>We all essentially have one Big problem, whenever we do some good 
        work, we expect someone to appreciate it. If nobody does, then we'll 
        be discouraged. When we are aware that we have done a good 
        job, why should we get discouraged just because some xyz 
        person doesn't see the importance of our achievement?. Always make 
        it a point to appreciate yourself when you feel like you have done a 
        good job. These appreciations go a long way to help you to be track 
        &amp; achieve success. Remember, those claps, cheers turn entire game 
        from one side to the other.
        </p>
        <p>Always believe in your abilities. Come on let's cultivate TI2 in all our 
        activities and achieve our goals!
        </p>
        <p><b>--Razikh</b><br/>
	</p>
    </section>
</article>