    <section>
        <br/><name><font face="Monotype Corsiva" color="#800000">Bubble E-book Corner</font></name>
        <p>
            Welcome to Bubble E-book corner. Every week a Technical and Non-technical e-book will be uploaded in this page. There would be short description about the e-book. Due to space constraint ealier uploaded e-bboks will be deleted. So save your copy today!!
             
        </p>
        <p>
          <font face="Monotype Corsiva" color="Red"><b> Non-Technical E-book: </b></font> 
            
        </p>
        <font face="Book Antiqua" color="black"><b>Bicycle Shop Murder by Robert Burton Robinson </b></font> 
        <p>
        </p>
        <p>
         Greg Tenorly lives a rather quiet and lonely life until the day a beautiful redhead walks into his office. Cynthia Blockerman claims her husband is abusing her and asks for Greg's help. The next day, Greg is selected as a juror for a murder trial. Now he finds himself on the same jury as Cynthia's husband. And the two men get into headed debates in the jury room. But after three residents of the town are murdered, including the abusive husband, Greg realizes his own life might be in danger. To make matters worse, the district attorney suspects that Greg and Cynthia are having an affair--motive for killing her husband. But Greg believes that someone outside Coreyville is behind all of the murders. So, he and Cynthia make a trip to Dallas to confront the infamous Buford Bellowin, a high-powered defense lawyer. But, their actions put them directly in the line of fire. So, now they have a hit man and the police hunting for them. Will their fate be prison or death? That might depend on who finds them first
        
        
        </p>
        
        <p>
              Click here to download...<b><a href="/ebooks/Bicycle_Shop_Murder_eBook.pdf">Bicycle Shop Murder by Robert Burton Robinson</a></b>
        </p> 
        
        
        <p>
          <font face="Monotype Corsiva" color="Red"><b> Technical E-book: </b></font> 
            
        </p>
        
         <p>
                  Will be uploaded soon...
         </p>
        
    </section>

