<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article>
    <title>Walking is a good exercise to tone your body </title>
    <author></author>
    <section>
       <p>
       Walking is a natural exercise. But today, it has become such a conscious activity/exercise that we’ll be desperate to get rid off and get on with another traveling media/heavy exercise without realizing its advantage. 
       </p>
       <p>
       Yes, walking which is a free, low impact activity is an effective exercise for people of all ages!! 
       </p>
       
       <p>
       Best part is it doesn’t require any equipment, specific timings or special training. Only optional thing which will enhance your experience is a good pair of walking shoes. 
Every step you take improves your health by controlling weight, reduces risk of chronic diseases by burning fat and lowering cholesterol.
        </p>
        <p>
        Question is, how much do you really need to walk? As per statistics, walking for 30 Mins is equivalent to Jogging for 15 Mins. Equal number of calories is burnt in both the activities. So why not do walking which is less stressful but yields same results!! 
And the reason why most of us hit the Gym is to reduce weight and tone body. As per research walking is very effective in slimming waist!!  
        </p>  
        <p>
       Ok, so what are those advantages which we aren’t aware of about walking?
        <br>
Few of the advantages of walking are,</br> 
        </p>
        
        <p> 
        <pre>
• Burns the calories – Any exercise does that. But the proportion with 
  walking is higher. 
• Slims your waist – Why to spend for it when its easily achievable by walk
• Reduces Stress – Walking is an excellent refreshing and relaxing activity. 
  Do I need to say how much fun it is walking in the park, across the beach 
  and streets? 
• Less stressful – Doesn’t stress your joints too much.
• Lowers blood pressure 
• Lowers Cholesterol
• Reduces risk chronic diseases
• Good get to gather exercise with family and friends
• Absolutely free!! No equipments are required. 
         </pre> 
         </p>
        
        <p>
        Ok, ok, advantages are fine…but is there any specific walking procedure? 
Well, unconscious natural walk itself provides all the above advantages, but you can achieve them much sooner and much effectively by including following methods in your daily walking activity,
        </p>
        
        <p>
        <pre>
• Walking up hills and down hills (Upside and downside streets ?)
• Walking road side slopes and sideways
• Dodging people. (Don’t you want to finish first?)
• Crossing the roads(Stopping and Starting activity which burns more calories)
• Walking on gross, gravel, foot path and roads
         </pre> 
         </p> 
         <p>
         And of course, Treadmill can also be used for walking exercise. Just that treadmill can never make you walk sideways and down hills!!
         </p>
         <p>
         If you are keen on losing weight…Just walking doesn’t ensure weight loss until proper diet is followed.
         </p>
         <p>
         Diet doesn’t mean that you should stop eating everything you like. It just means to consume them in proper quantity. 
         </p>
         <p>
         Every body should calculate their daily calorie intake and must not exceed that value. Now if you are not aware how to manage calorie intake, lets put following rules while taking food,
         </p>
        <p>
         <pre>
• Avoid eating full stomach. You don’t need to eat full. Just eat enough 
  food to suppress that hunger feeling. So this means that you can have 
  more than 3 times a day but only as much as required. Eating full 
  stomach puts load on digestive system especially on liver. 
• Prefer chicken/egg over red meat. 
• Have as many green vegetables as you want.
• Fruits are the best means to suppress hunger and add enough vitamins, 
  calories to you daily intake. Especially fruits like Apple suppress 
  hunger for a very long time.
• Don’t avoid Rice/means of starch which is very much required for the body. 
• Wheat/bread related products are good alternatives to heavy food.
• Finish your dinner at least 3 Hrs before going to bed. 
• Go for a long walk say an hour before going to bed to keep that metabolic 
  activity active while you sleep to burn calories. 
• Avoid simply eating snacks if you are not feeling hungry. Don’t get tempted 
  to eat. Avoiding this will go a long way in keeping you healthy. 
• Reduce oil intake. Prefer vegetable oil over other oils.
• Have tea once a day. As even a cup of tea gives you around 300 calories!!!
          </pre>
          </p> 
                   
         <p>
         This is my personal experience. I tried above walking and diet methods and lost 8 kilos in 3 months! Let me know your experience…
         </p>
         
         <p>
         Keep walking for a healthy Life…
         </p>
         
        <p><b>--Razikh</b><br/>
	</p>
    </section>
</article>
