<document>
    <section>
        <name>About Bubble</name>

        <p color='black'>
        Bubble is aimed at providing services across various domains ranging from
        Technical to classifieds. 
        </p><p color='black'>
        The Tech Space (technical article section) is intended to present
        information/solutions to the real time issues in development &amp; testing
        environments. We do not intend to publish generic tutorials as they are
        very well available across the web. Here aim is to solve some specific
        issue or provide information to enhance existing mechanism.
        </p><p color='black'>
        The Projects section is mainly caters to the needs of Engineering/professional
        students looking for academic projects. Here we intend to publish/provide
        projects across Networking, Database &amp; Application Programming domains
        which maps closely to the products developed by the organisations. Thus
        bridging the gap between a student and a professional
        </p><p color='black'>
        One of the Core values of Bubble is to enable every vendor to get online
        with least investment. In this regard we intend to provide classifieds
        services &amp; customized vendor page.         
        </p><p color='black'>
        We undertake trainings for students and corporate employees. Trainings
        will be tailored to the need of the audience. Our corporate trainers are
        trained to provide trainings to different categories of audiences ranging
        from students to the industry experts.
        </p><p color='black'>
        Last but not the least is to accumulate &amp; provide information on
        various events across the city, articles on trekking, health, life &amp;
        place holder to share nature photography &amp; Bubble Forum to discuss
        &amp; share knowledge.            
        </p><p>
            -- Bubble Team
        </p>
            
    </section>
</document>
