<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<article>
    <title>Sinhagad</title>
    <author><a href="mailto:razikh@gmail.com">-Razikh</a></author>
    <section>
        <p>
            Sinhagad is one of the closest forts around pune and the best one for all 
            those who want to try trekking.  <br>The best part of this is there is clearly 
            defined trek trail (path) right from the beginning till the </br>top along with 
            few short cuts here n there. <br>You can also reach the fort by road though 
           the road is pathetic and motor cycle drive is risky.</br>     
          </p>
          
        <p>Sinhagad is located at approx 30 KMs from Shivajinagar Bus stop/Rly station.
            Reaching Sinhagad <br>is pretty straight forward. From Shivajinagar or 
            corporation or Pune railway station </br>go towards 
            Karve road---&gt; Null stop ---&gt; Swargate and hit Sinhagad Road.         
            </p>
        <p>Once on Sinhagad road, keep going straight for about 20Kms. 
        In between you will come across diversion <br>for Panshet, keep left for Sinhagad. 
        Then you will find another diversion, the left turn takes you to the top</br> 
        by road. Keep right and continue to reach village at the base of the Sinhagad.
         You can park vehicle there, and  start trekking up. Usually Saturday &amp; 
         Sunday lot many enthusiasts trek Sinhagad. On the way to the top you will 
         find localites selling refreshments.  <br/>
        </p>
        <p>There is one small temple in between which indicates half of the way of trek.
         With normal, first time <br>doers speed; it will take max 1Hr 30 Mins to reach the top.   
        </br></p>
        <p>Though the fort is spoiled, it still provides a very nice view of the 
        surrounding places from the top &amp; the <br>environment during Rainy season 
        is just awesome. </br> It attracts lot many tourists regularly &amp;favorite 
        destination for adventurous college goers, professionals &amp; families.
        You will find localites serving maharashtrian delicacies.        
        </p>
        
        <p>
        
<pre>
Some Specs :)

Trek Type: Easy 

Total Distance: Approx 2-3 KMs one side. 

Travel time from Shivajinagar: Approx 1Hr 

Quality of the Road: last 2-3 KMs is pathetic otherwise manageable. 
Good at few places.

What not to be missed: Good Shoes as there is lot of gravel &amp; big 
stones on the trek path. 

Find pics below of the fort &amp; surroundings,
</pre>
        
        </p>
      
   <p>
   
    <table style="width: 100%" cellspacing="3">
	<tr>
		<td>
		<img src="http://www.bubble.co.in/images/trek/sinh1.jpg" width="250" height="188"></img></td>
		<td><img src="../../../images/trek/sinh2.jpg" width="250" height="188"></img> </td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td><img src="http://www.bubble.co.in/images/trek/sinh3.jpg" width="250" height="188" /></td>
		<td><img src="../../../images/trek/sinh4.jpg" width="250" height="188"></img></td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td><img src="../../../images/trek/sinh5.jpg" width="250" height="188"></img></td>
		<td><img src="../../../images/trek/sinh6.jpg" width="250" height="188"></img></td>
	</tr>
	<tr>
		<td><img src="../../../images/trek/sinh7.jpg" width="250" height="188"></img></td>
		<td><img src="../../../images/trek/sinh8.jpg" width="250" height="188"></img></td>
	</tr>
</table>

   
   
   </p>


  <p><b>--Razikh</b><br/>
	</p>
    </section>
</article>